（ナルト）ハックション！
何だ？　虫？
What's this?
A bug. Here, of all places?
こんなとこに…
お前　ずいぶんと冒険好きだな。
You must be adventurous.
Going all the way to
the Land of Lightning.
雷の国まで行くなんて。
Speaking of bugs,
そういや　虫っていえば
誰かを思い出しそうな。
why does this remind me
of someone?
Um… Let's see.
えっと…　えっと…。
"Friends You Can Count On"
ねえ　これから戦争になるって
ほんとなの？
Hey, is it true that a war is starting?
あぁ
うちの父ちゃんも言ってたぜ。
Yeah. My dad was saying we're going
to pulverize the Akatsuki.
暁を　ぶっ倒すんだって。
（シノ）そうだ。　これから忍世界の
未来が決まる戦争が始まる。
It's true.
A war that will decide the future
of the shinobi world will begin.
シノ先生も戦地へ行くの？
Will you be going to battle too,
Shino Sensei?
あぁ。
先生は怖くねえのかよ？
Yes.
Are you scared, Sensei?
バカ！　先生が怖いわけないだろ。
Stupid! Sensei would never be scared.
いや　そんなことはない。
え！？
No, you're wrong.
先生が　怖いの？
ウソ…。
Are you scared?
No way.
だが　必ず生きて帰るという
自信はある。
But I'm confident that
I will come back alive.
どうして？
Why?
なぜなら　俺には
信頼できる仲間がいるからだ。
It's because I have friends
that I trust.
♪～
《キバ：よし！　両手がふさがれば》
All right. If I can block both hands…
（スイカ）む！？
貴様たちがオトリで　やつが本命か。
So you two are the decoys
and he's the main one!
だが…。
However…
《火遁　業火球の術！》
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu.
たいがい
遠隔の術を得意とする者は→
Those who specialize
in long-distance jutsu
接近戦が苦手だ。
tend to be weak in close combat.
ぐあっ！
（スイカ）弱すぎる。
しょせん蟲使いなど　この程度よ。
You're too weak.
But I guess that's what you get
with an insect master.
シノ！
（ヒナタ）大丈夫！？　シノ君。
Shino!
Are you all right, Shino?
((スイカ：弱すぎる。
しょせん蟲使いなど　この程度よ))
You're too weak.
But I guess that's what you get
with an insect master.
（紅）そう…
逃げられてしまったのね。
I see. He got away.
面目ねえ。
I'm ashamed of myself.
気にしなくていいわ。
Don't worry about it.
あれから　追加情報で
わかったことだけど→
We received more intel afterwards.
やつは滝隠れの上忍から抜けて
盗賊になった男よ。
He's a jonin from
the Village Hidden in the Waterfalls
who went rogue and
became a bandit.
あなたたちが　かなわなくても
しかたのない相手だった。
It just couldn't be helped if
you were no match for him.
綱手様には
私から報告をしておくわ。
I'll make the report to Lady Hokage.
申し訳ありません。
We're very sorry.
くれぐれも　シノを責めては駄目よ。
わかってるよ。
Don't blame Shino.
I know. But he's shut himself away
in his house.
でも　あいつ家に閉じこもったまま
出てきやしねえ。
プライドが高いやつだからな。
That guy has so much pride.
困ったわね。
That's a problem.
ねえ　あなたたちで
シノを立ち直らせてあげて。
Listen. I want you to help him
get back on his feet.
え？
でも　どうやって？
How are we supposed to do that?
あいつは　俺たちの言うことなんて
耳を貸さねえぜ。
He wouldn't listen to us.
では　命令します。
Well, this is an order.
あなたたちで
里の南にある温泉地に行きなさい。
I want you to go to the hot springs
on the south side of the village.
シノにも　そう言って。
Take Shino.
♪～
（シノ）何か用か？
（キバ）バレたか…。
What do you want?
You're on to us.
（ヒナタ）シノ君　怪我　大丈夫？
（シノ）心配ない。　何の用だ？
Shino, how is your wound?
It's nothing to worry about.
What do you want?
なんだよ
用がなくて来ちゃ駄目か？
What's wrong with us
just coming to visit?
俺たち八班だろ？
Aren't we all on Squad 8?
気にするなよ。　いいじゃねえか
１回くらい負けたって。
Don't worry about it.
There's nothing wrong
with losing once.
相手は上忍だったんだ。
Our enemy was a jonin,
and we're not even chunin yet.
まだ俺たちは
中忍にもなってねえんだぜ。
かなわなくて当たり前だろ。
It's a given that he's going
to be better than us.
まぁ　おめえは自分が強いって
自惚れがすげえからよ→
Well, you have it in your head
that you're strong,
so I guess it came as a big shock.
ショックが　でかいんだろうけど。
キバ君…。
K-Kiba…
Or are you depressed
about something else?
なんだよ
落ち込んでんのは別のことか？
まさか　ナルトの　お前へのリアクションが
薄いってこととか？
Don't tell me you're upset about
Naruto's indifference towards you?
んなこと気にするなよ。
Don't let it get to you.
あいつは俺と違って
ガサツなところがあるからな。
Unlike me, he can be pretty rude.
あぁ　わかった！
気にしてんのは→
Oh, I get it.
The fact that you were
the only one who didn't participate
サスケの奪回作戦に１人だけ
参加できなかったことか？
in the Sasuke retrieval mission
is still weighing on you.
でもよ　あの時は　お前
別の任務についてたんだ。
You were on a different mission then,
so it couldn't be helped.
しかたねえだろ。
帰れ！
Get lost!
帰らねえ。　俺たちは　これから
里の南にある温泉地に行くんだ。
Nope. We're heading out
to a hot spring
in the southern part of the village.
なぜ？
Why?
Your wound will heal faster there and…
そのほうが
シノ君の傷も早く治るだろうし。
行くつもりはない。
I have no intention of going.
I figured you would say that.
まぁ　そう言うとは思ったけどよ。
ところが　お前は断れないんだな。
But you can't refuse.
It's an order.
これは命令だからな。
ったく…　絡みづらい野郎だぜ。
Man, he's so hard to be around.
あれから
ひと言も口利かねえしよ。
He hasn't spoken a word to us.
《キバ君も十分絡みづらいけど…》
You're just as difficult
to be around, Kiba.
MORI-NO-YU
HOT SPRING
やっと着いた！
今日は　ゆっくり休もうぜ。
We're finally here.
Let's just rest up today.
うん。
さ～て
ひとっ風呂浴びようぜ　赤丸！
All right, Akamaru,
let's go take a soak.
（赤丸）ワン！
イヤッホ～！
Yahoo!
うわっ！
なんだ　お前も入るのか。
What? Are you coming too?
悪いか？
あぁ　いや…。
Do you have a problem
with that?
N-No.
《そういや　こいつの裸って…
まさか蟲だらけ？
I hope that when he's naked,
he's not covered in insects…
うぅ！　きもっ》
Gross!
入らないのか？
Aren't you coming in?
《百聞は一見にしかず》
Well I guess seeing is believing!
入るぜ！
I sure am!
《普通じゃねえか…》
He's pretty normal.
あぁ…　湯あたりした。
I think I stayed in too long.
（キバ）うわ～！
な…　何だ　これ！？
What the hell is that?!
（ヒナタ）その練習
私たちも混ぜてもらっていい？
Can we train with you?
何やってんだよ？
何も。
What are you doing?
Nothing.
まったく素直じゃねえな　お前は。
Why aren't you being up
front with us?
隠すなよ　体術の訓練だろ？
だったら　みんなでやらない？
Don't hide it.
You're practicing taijutsu, aren't you?
Let's train together!
どうせ　私たちも
そのつもりで来たから。
Besides, that's why we came here.
どういうことだ？
What are you up to?
おめえを鍛えて
もっと強くするんだよ。
We're going to train with you
and make you stronger.
おめえみてえに
プライドの高いやつが立ち直るには→
This is the only way to help a proud guy
like you get back on his feet.
それしか方法はねえ。
まぁ　お前だけじゃなく
俺たちも一緒に訓練積めば→
And if we get some training in
at the same time,
we'll be killing two birds
with one stone.
一石二鳥だしな。
シノ君が問題だと
思っているのは→
You're concerned about
being forced into close combat
蟲の操作中　接近戦に
持ち込まれた時のことだよね。
while manipulating your insects, right?
だから　そこを狙われても→
That's why you're training in taijutsu.
So that you won't lose
when you're targeted.
負けない体術を
身につけようとしている。
そのとおりだ。
だったら　一緒にやろう。
You're correct.
So let's train together.
Taijutsu training is more effective
when you have a partner.
体術なら　１人より
相手がいるほうが効率的だし。
わ…　私が相手じゃ
物足りないかもしれないけど→
I-I may not be that skilled in taijutsu,
but I think I can help.
少しは役に立てると思う。
I think the first thing is speed.
まずは　スピードだと思うんだ。
If you can overwhelm your opponent
with a lot of moves,
手数で相手を
圧倒することができれば→
you can prevent him
from weaving signs.
相手が印を結ぶのを
封じることができるし。
異論はない。
いきます。
I have no objections.
I'll begin.
♪～
もっとスピードを上げるよ。
I'm going to pick up the speed.
おぉ　ヒナタのやつ　本気だぜ。
Hinata is serious about this.
Hey, hey!
おらおら！　ヒナタに　やり込められて
悔しくねえのか？
Aren't you upset that Hinata
got the better of you?
悔しくはない。　なぜなら→
No, I'm not.
That's because I don't judge people.
俺は　どんな相手であろうと
差別はしない。
ったく　絡みづれえ。
I can't get a rise out of this guy.
Shino, think of me as
that bandit shinobi.
シノ君　私を
あの盗賊忍者だと思って。
You're too weak.
((弱すぎる。
しょせん蟲使いなど　この程度よ))
But I guess that's what you get
with an insect master.
調子が出てきたね。
You're starting to get the hang of it.
おら！
敵が常に１人だとはかぎらねえ！
Here!
You're not always going to face
a single opponent!
よ～く周りを見ろ！
Pay close attention to
your surroundings.
擬獣忍法四脚の術！
Beast Mimicry Ninja Art!
All-Four Jutsu!
スピードと視野がついてきたら
最後は　イメージだよ。
Once you develop your speed and
field of vision, next is visualization.
何だよ　イメージって。
What's "visualization"?
えっと　敵を
見極めるってことなんだけど…。
Well, it's seeing through your opponent.
つまり　敵の弱点はどこか→
Like knowing his weakness and
not letting him get the advantage?
地の利は生かせないか
カウンターを狙えるか→
Having a counterstrategy and always
keeping it in mind when you fight?
そういうことを考えながら
戦う…　ということだな？
そう　そのとおり。
Yes, exactly!
なるほどな。
確かに手数が多いと→
I see.
When you have a lot of moves,
目先のことで
頭がいっぱいになって→
you're only thinking about
what's directly in front of you,
そういうことは
考えられなくなっちまうからな。
and you lose focus of other things.
でも　大丈夫だ。
俺には頭脳がもう１つあるからな。
But I don't need to worry.
I have one more brain.
な？　赤丸。
ワンワン！
Right, Akamaru?
MORI-NO-YU
HOT SPRINGS
（キバ）ギャ～ッ！
WOMEN
《わ…　私　何やってるんだろう…。
W-What am I doing?
でも　隣が気になる》
I'm worried about
the two next door!
♪～
《集中してやがんな　シノのやつ。
Shino is really focused.
みるみる腕が上がってるぜ》
He's improving right before
my very eyes.
《すごい上達の仕方。
Such amazing progress.
シノ君とは
手合わせしたことなかったけど→
I've never sparred with Shino,
接近戦の潜在能力が
ここまで高いなんて…。
but I didn't expect him to
be this good in close combat.
けど　私も
負けるわけにはいかない》
Still, I cannot lose!
さ～て　最終テストといくか　赤丸。
ワン！
Now then.
Let's go with the final test, Akamaru!
牙通牙！
Fang Over Fang!
何の真似だ！
What's the big idea?
よくかわしたな。
今のが　最終テストだ。
You dodged that well.
That was the final test.
なに…？
俺の牙通牙はな→
What?
In ninjutsu, my Fang Over Fang
ranks as the fastest.
忍術の中でも　スピードはいちばんだ。
死角からの牙通牙をかわせりゃ
たいしたもんだぜ。
Dodging my Fang Over Fang from
a blind spot is quite impressive.
訓練は終わりだ。
Your training is complete.
それじゃ　これで
八班のスリーマンセルは復活だね。
And that means Squad 8
has been revived.
だな！
Right!
いいや…　俺は　お前たちと
スリーマンセルを組む気はない。
No, I have no interest in being part
of your three-man squad.
どうしてだよ！？
Why not?!
なぜなら　俺には
その資格がないからだ。
Because I have no right
to be part of it.
確かに　俺の強さは増した。
だが　それでも→
Without a doubt,
I have grown stronger.
However, I'm not confident enough
to watch your backs.
俺には　お前たちの背中を守る
自信はない。
シノ君…。
Shino.
すまない…。
I'm sorry.
てめえ！
よくそんなことが言えるな！
Hey! How dare you say that to us!
俺だって　ヒナタだって→
Hinata and I both did our best
to help you get back on your feet!
てめえを立ち直らせるために
今まで努力してきたんだろうが！
感謝はしている。
ざけんな！
And believe me, I'm grateful.
Don't give me that!
やめて！　キバ君！
Stop it, Kiba!
てめえが　そんな情けねえやつ
だとは　思ってもみなかったぜ。
I didn't think you were so pitiful.
ワン！　ワン！
これって　紅先生からの連絡鳩。
It's Kurenai's Sensei's
messenger pigeon.
見ろよ。
Read this.
シノ君！　あの盗賊が近くに！
Shino, that bandit is near!
俺は行くぜ。
で　でも→
I'm going!
Oh, but it says not to engage until
Kurenai Sensei gets here!
手紙には　紅先生が着くまで
戦うなって…。
わかってるって。
戦わなきゃいいんだろ。
I know that!
We won't fight him. Tracking is
Squad 8's specialty!
尾行は　俺たち八班のお家芸だ。
とにかく　俺は行く。
今度こそ　やつを逃がさねえ！
So I'm going. And this time,
he's not going to get away!
私も行きます。
I'm coming with you!
じゃあ…　あばよ　シノ！
So long, Shino!
ワン！
シノ君…　さっき　キバ君のこぶしを
どうしてよけなかったの？
Shino, why didn't you avoid
Kiba's punch earlier?
今のシノ君なら　できたのに。
I know you can now.
それは…。
私は　今でも八班の背中は→
That's because…
I still believe that Squad 8 can
count on you to protect us, Shino.
シノ君が守ってくれてると
信じてる。
この先だ。
It's up ahead.
白眼！
Byakugan!
（ヒナタ）見つけた！
Found him!
とりあえず　尾行だ。
うん。
Anyway, let's just track him!
Right!
《スイカ：来たか…》
They're here.
クゥ～ン。
この臭い…　気づかれたか！？
This scent. He's on to us.
向こうは　尾行だけじゃ
済ましてくれないようだぜ。
Looks like he's not going to
just let us track him.
来るぞ！
Here he comes!
クソッ！
Fire Style! Red Spider!
火遁！　紅地蜘蛛！
やばい！　上に行くしかねえ！
Damn it! The only way to go is up!
キバ君　これ！
Kiba! Look!
囲まれたか…。
We're surrounded.
また　お前らか。
身のほどを知ることも必要だ。
You guys again.
You should know your place!
蒼女郎！
Blue Joro Spider!
（スイカ）逃がさねえよ。
I won't let you escape!
火遁！　火炎旋風！
Fire Style! Flame Hurricane!
（キバ／ヒナタ）うわぁ～っ！
フン　終わったな。
It's over.
なに？　これは　蟲。
These are insects.
シノ。
シノ君。
– Shino!
また貴様か。　蒼女郎。
You again!
Blue Joro Spider!
クッ　これじゃ動けねえ。
I can't move like this!
まずは貴様からだ。
シノ！
シノ君！
I'll start with you first!
– Shino!
お前の弱点は知っている。　ハァッ！
I know your weakness.
((弱すぎる。
所詮　蟲使いなどこの程度よ))
You're too weak.
But I guess that's what you get
with an insect master.
なに！？
What?!
ならば。
Well then!
バカな。
俺はお前には負けない。
Ridiculous!
I will not lose to you.
なぜなら俺は
あのときの俺ではないからだ。
That's because I'm not
the same person I was back then.
《接近戦が駄目なら…。
If close combat isn't
going to work, then…
印が結べん》
What? I can't weave signs.
まだ　こんなものではない！
Not yet! Not by a long shot!
グァッ。
よくも俺の仲間を苦しめたな。
How dare you hurt my friends!
よくも俺と蟲を侮辱したな。
グァッ！
How dare you insult me and my insects!
強え　シノ。
食らえ　鉄山靠。
Shino is so strong.
Take that!
Iron Tackle!
ヌァ～ッ！
柔拳。
グァッ。
Gentle Fist!
いくぜ　赤丸。
ワン。
Let's go, Akamaru!
とどめだ。
Let's finish him!
グァ～ッ！
紅先生。
Kurenai Sensei!
どうやら
私の出番はなかったようね。
I guess there's nothing
for me to do here.
ヘッ　当たり前だぜ。
Of course not!
でも　倒せたのは
ほとんどシノ君のおかげだけど。
But it was mostly Shino's work.
まあな。
ク～ン。
Well, yeah…
これで八班は本当に復活ね。
Looks like Squad 8 has made
a full recovery!
ああ。　シノ　俺はなおめえにだったら
いつだって背中を預けるぜ。
Yup!
Shino, I'd put my life in
your hands any time.
私も。
わかった。　なぜなら…。
Me too.
All right. That's because…
俺たちの間に
理屈はいらねえっつ～の。
You don't have to reason with us!
そうだな。
I guess not.
ここまで来たらせっかくだもの
温泉に入らないとね。
Since I made it all the way out here,
I thought I should have a soak
in the hot spring.
いいお湯ですね。
It feels wonderful.
Imagine, beating him by yourselves.
それにしても　あなたたちだけで
勝てるなんて→
ほんとに強くなったわ。
You've really gotten strong.
でも　あなたとキバ　２人で
来たときはちょっと焦ったけど。
But I admit I nearly panicked when
it was just you and Kiba.
もしかして紅先生
私たちのことずっと見てました？
Kurenai Sensei, by any chance,
were you watching us
the whole time?
なんのこと？
What are you talking about?
まさか　あの忍者がこの温泉の
近くに潜伏してたのも…。
偶然よ　偶然。
ウギャ～ッ！
てめぇ　シノ　いいかげんにしろよ。
お前たちにもいつかわかる。
戦いは怖くない。
なぜなら自分の背中は必ず
仲間が守ってくれている。
（みんな）うん。
わかった。
ふわぁ～　誰だっけかな？
やっぱ思い出せねえや。
クシュンッ。　ん？　ん？
（美空）
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくり　お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。